Preliminary Inventory to the John Raymond Hutchinson Papers 1918-1961
Hoover Institution Archives
John Raymond Hutchinson papers
1918-1961
52002
Hutchinson, John R.
5 manuscript boxes, 2 cubic foot boxes, 2 envelopes, 5 phonorecords (4.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, film scripts, printed matter, photographs, filmstrips, and phonorecords, relating to the production of U.S. propaganda film by the Office of War Information for distribution in China during World War II, and to the history of television in the U.S.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United States. Office of War Information.; Education.; Propaganda, American--China.; Television in education--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.; China.; United States--Foreign relations.; Phonorecords.
Container List
- Description of filmstrips., 1
- Letter from Gus Paton (served with the OSS); correspondence between Hutchinson and Dr. Gerald F. Winfield, U.S. Embassy China; one list "Booking Records: Filmstrips;" one list "Projectors in Field;" one list "Material in Story File.", 2
- Four "Picture Lists" (titles of films).
- Six drawings by "The Cowboy Artist," Charles M. Russell.
- Miscellaneous material: pamphlets (Hoover Dam, banking panic), also Chinese money which was sent with Gus Paton's letter.
- "Teacher's Manual of Instructions on the Use of Filmstrips."
- Photo album: "Early TV in America.", 3
- Photo album: "Some interesting `Firsts' in TV."
- Television scripts "Setting the Stage" for the Chronicles of America Photoplays. Scripts prepared and presented by Hutchinson. New York City, 1941.
- Duplicate to 3c (without scripts nos. 6 & 7).
- Correspondence and miscellaneous items:, 4
  - 18 letters and 3 cards from Herbert Hoover to Hutchinson (orig.).
  - Letters (1936-1961), including correspondents such as Presidents Wilson and Taft, General MacArthur, Gen. Robert Wood, LaGuardia, etc. Also autographs and a "Certificate of Honor...Four-Minute Man of the Committee on Public Information during the War of 1917-1918" for Mrs. Hutchinson's father, James. C. Holmes, 1918.
  - Shooting script to the motion picture, "Union Pacific," 1938, with five autographs.
  - Research notes for Cecil B. DeMille's production, "Union Pacific." 1938.
  - "Television was Fun", a resume of BBC-TV, July 1936-Sept. 1939, by Hutchinson. Scripts, photos, and duplicates.
  - Heath, Eric. "Writing for Television." Los Angeles, California, Research Publ. Co., 1950. 325 p. (autographed copy).
- Committee on Television - evaluation of programs (first group work of this type in America and perhaps anywhere)., 5
  - Two envelopes of printed articles by Hutchinson on TV.
  - Miscellaneous material: 11 flags used on the "Declaration of Independence" program; pencil box from the Civil War; WW I draft capsule.
  - Three magazines with articles on TV: Fortune, April and May, 1939, and Radio Age, April 1946.
  - Mrs. Hutchinson's grandmother's certificate as a member of the "Daughters of the American Revolution."
  - Speech and photo of Abraham Lincoln and 10 paintings (?) from the L.H. Bogart (?) collection.
  - Miscellaneous material on Thomas Jefferson High Scool, Elizabeth, N.J. where Mr. Hutchinson taught, (18 photos, one letter).
  - Miscellaneous Red Cross material (Mrs. Hutchinson's activities as a Gray Lady).
  - Blue prints of a study of Museums here and abroad, by Arthur E. Krows.
- Audiovisual materials
  - Chronicles of America Photoplay Television sound recording (pt. 1-2), 1941 September 18 (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
    A discussion of the American Revolution as a lead-in to a movie. It focuses on the Eastern campaign of Washington against Clinton and Cornwallis, which would culminate in Yorktown. Special note is made of French assistance to the Americans. NBC label. 2 discs. Use copy reference number: 52002_a_0002898
  - DGSM 1147 - 1 (School, pt. 1 and 2) (2 records) (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
  - RCA Victor presents Television
  - 106 filmstrips, 324 negatives. (in 2 cubic foot boxes at end of collection)
  - Oil portrait of Mrs. Hutchinson (10.V)